Someone's going down
Flushed Away is a adventure, animation, comedy film directed by David Bowers.
London high-society mouse, Roddy is flushed down the
toilet by Sid, a common sewer rat.
Hang on for a madcap adventure deep in the sewer bowels of Ratropolis, where Roddy meets the
resourceful Rita, the rodent-hating Toad and his faithful thugs, Spike and Whitey.
Roddy (voice), played by Hugh Jackman.
Rita (voice), played by Kate Winslet.
The Toad (voice), played by Ian McKellen.
Le Frog (voice), played by Jean Reno.
Whitey (voice), played by Bill Nighy.
Spike (voice), played by Andy Serkis.
Flushed Away is a 2006 animated adventure comedy film produced by
DreamWorks Animation SKG and Aardman Features.
The film was directed by David Bowers and Sam Fell, and written by Dick
Clement, Ian La Frenais, Chris Lloyd, Joe Keenan and Will Davies.
The film stars the voices of Hugh Jackman, Kate Winslet, Ian McKellen,
Shane Richie, Bill Nighy, Andy Serkis and Jean Reno.
In the film, a fancy rat named Roddy St.
James is flushed down the toilet in his Kensington apartment and befriends a scavenger
named Rita Malone in order to get back home while evading a sinister toad.
Flushed Away was the third and final DreamWorks and Aardman co-production following
Chicken Run (2000) and Wallace & Gromit: The Curse of the Were-Rabbit (2005).
Director Fell conceived the concept of rats falling in love
in the sewers while working on Chicken Run.
In 2001, Fell developed a story and pitched it to DreamWorks.
The project was announced in July 2002, followed by comedy writing duo Clement and La Frenais
being contracted to write the script, which had the working title Ratropolis.
In 2003, Bowers joined Fell as co-director.
It was the first Aardman project made primarily in CGI animation instead of using their usual
claymation – this was because using water on plasticine models could damage them.
The film's premiere was held on 22 October 2006 during the Tokyo International Film Festival, followed by a wide release in
the United States by Paramount Pictures on 3 November 2006, and in the United Kingdom by UIP on 1 December.
It received positive reviews from critics, but was a box-office disappointment, grossing $178 million against a
$149 million production budget, resulting in an estimated loss of $109 million for the studios.
The failure led to Aardman ending its collaboration deal with DreamWorks.
The film received nominations for the BAFTA Award and
Critics' Choice Award for Best Animated Feature.
It received eight nominations at the 34th Annie Awards, winning five,
including for the screenplay and, for McKellen, Voice Acting.
The film explores themes of ship, london, england, return, villain, girlfriend.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.